你好
Hello!
欧文
Irving!
- 是我 我在上面 - 马克
- It's me. I'm up here! - Mark!
对
Yeah!
嘿
Hey!
现在什么情况
What's happening?
我们在哪里
Where are we?
完全搞不懂状况
I have no fucking idea,
但那边有一条通上悬崖的路
but there's a path up the cliff right down there!
你希望我上来吗
Do you want me to come up?
对啊
Well, yeah!
我在冰上呢 我在该死的冰上
I'm on the ice. I'm on the fucking ice!
试着离开冰面 来吧
Maybe get off of it. Come on!
我过来了
I'm coming!
我...
I'm--
过来了
I'm coming!
小心点
Be careful!
这里很陡
It's very steep!
欧文
Irving.
赫莉
Helly!
你是从哪儿来的
Where did you come from?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们在这里做什么
What are we doing out here?
到这上面来
Up here!
往我声音的方向走
Follow my voice!
马克
Mark!
在这里
Up here!
马克
Mark.
嘿
Hey!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
- 你也是在冰上醒来的吗  - 对
- Did you wake up on the ice too? - Yeah.
- 你呢  - 在悬崖上
- What about you? - On the cliff.
天啊
Oh, my God.
- 是你们吗  - 当然是我们
- Is it you? - Of course it's us.
要命啊
Holy shit!
这可是外面
Out-fucking-side.
天啊 我就知道外面没有天花板
Oh, my God. I mean, I knew there was no actual ceiling,
但这也太疯狂了
but this is fucking insane.
有人吗
Hello?
什么声音
What is that?
(欢迎 播放曲目)
早上好 精检员们
Good morning, Refiners.
我是公司的米尔奇克先生 很激动能欢迎大家
This is Mr. Milchick from work, and I'm thrilled to welcome you
来到你们的首次...
to your first ever
(卢蒙)
...户外团建活动
outdoor retreat and team-building occurrence.
本次户外团建活动是 为满足你们对见到外面世界的渴望
This ORTBO is in response to your desire to see the outside world.
经你们外面的自己同意
With your outies' blessings,
你们将在接下来的两个历日 在迪特伊根国家森林公园远足
you will spend the next two calendar days walking the meadows,
欣赏这里的草地 灌丛 荆棘和溪流
thickets, brambles and brooks that make up the Dieter Eagan National Forest.
迪特伊根是谁
Who the fuck is Dieter Eagan?
迪特伊根
Dieter Eagan?
你们中的一些人可能正默默好奇 渴望了解更多
Some of you may be quietly yearning to learn more.
你所寻找的答案在附录四中
The truth you seek lies within the fourth appendix.
基尔在临终前口述了附录四的内容
Kier dictated a fourth appendix in his final hours of life,
由于内容过于神圣 其在分离层被禁止
a text of such sanctity that it is forbidden upon the severed floor.
它正在剪刀洞穴等待你们
It's waiting for you in Scissor Cave,
正是在那个洞窟中
the very same grotto
基尔伊根第一次驯服了四脾气
where Kier Eagan tamed the four tempers for the very first time.
请记住
And do remember,
“务必追循基尔之道 反之即受自然之怒”
"Stray not from Kier's path, lest you roil nature's wrath."
路上你们将获得帮助
There will be help along the way.
祝愉快顺利 宏观数据精检部
Happy fortunes, MDR.
剪刀洞穴
Scissor Cave.
那是什么鬼
What the fuck is that?
他看起来像马克
He looks like Mark.
米尔奇克说我们在路上会获得帮助
Milchick said there'd be help along the way.
那大骗子嘴里的话 我一个字都不信
I wouldn't trust a word out of that mountebank's mouth.
就算是电视版本的也不信
Not even televisually.
我们现在也没什么选择了 欧文
Not like we have a lot of other options right now, Irv.
等一下
Wait.
(四)
(给迪特)
“第一章
"Chapter one.
我不是独自来到这世上的
I was not born into this world alone.
我与另一个人曾同处于母亲的腹中
The lodgings of my mother's womb I shared with another,
他是我的孪生兄弟 名叫迪特”
a twin brother who was called Dieter."
基尔有个双胞胎兄弟
Kier had a twin?
那些东西就是
That's what those things are.
对
Yeah.
“在婴孩时期 他是我的密友 但随着我们成长为少年
"In infancy, he was my bosom friend. But as we blossomed into boyhood,
他恳求我和他一起到树林中 过贫民的日子
he beseeched me to take to the wood with him to live as paupers.
我的手足情左右了我的理智判断
My love for my twin unbalancing my judgment,
我应允了 于是我们进入树林 向着...”
I acceded, and we ventured into the wood towards"...
(悲哀谷)
“...悲哀谷行进”
"Woe's Hollow."
(悲哀谷地图)
所以我们要跟随兄弟俩的脚步
So, we're to walk in the brothers' footsteps.
“在这个时间 他总是这样蹑手蹑脚
"He always crept like this at this hour.
- 在花草的掩护下 我的兄弟...” - ...掩护下 我的兄弟
- Once concealed by flora, my brother"... - ...flora, my brother
解放了自我
unfastened himself.
他的狂热莫名与树林的音乐产生了共鸣
The din of his fervor fell strangely into concert with the music of the wood.
他的每一次猛推...
His every thrust found rhythm
- 与蟋蟀的颤鸣... - “颤鸣”
- with the trill of the crickets... - ..."trill of the crickets"...
- 和风的低吟... - “和风的低吟”
- ...and the moaning of the wind... - ..."and the moaning of the wind"...
- 和瑞雪融化的节拍同步 - “和瑞雪融化的节拍同步”
- ...and the snowfall's yearly thaw. - ..."and the snowfall's yearly thaw."
那天晚上 迪特成为了
Dieter became, on that night
- 大自然的乐器 - “大自然的乐器”
- an instrument of nature... - ..."an instrument of nature"...
- 而大自然... - “而大自然优雅地演奏着迪特
- ...and nature played Dieter... - "and nature played Dieter with elegance.
我只得听着
I had no choice but to listen
他将自己的血脉洒在土壤上”
as he spilt his lineage upon the soil."
现在轮到我出现了
Now there's a me one.
你还好吗
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
只是希望我们知道要去哪
I just wish I knew where we were going.
该死
Fuck.
你和赫莉刚才在后面聊什么
What were you and Helly talking about back there?
你说什么时候
When?
我不信任她
I don't trust her.
我觉得她没有把外面的自己 看到的东西如实告诉我们
I think she might be lying about what her outie saw.
为什么这么觉得
Why would you think that?
晚上工作的园丁
Night gardeners.
你显然无法客观看待她
It's clear you do not have an objective perspective
因为你对她有感情
due to your feelings for her.
我对她的感情不会影响任何事 好吗...
My feelings for her have nothing to do with anything, okay--
什么鬼
What the fuck?
那是什么
What is it?
我不知道
I don't know.
看起来像海豹
Looks like a seal.
为什么它样子这么惨
Why does it look so messed up?
不知道 也许死了就是这样
I don't know. Maybe this is what dead things look like.
我们应该吃了它
We should eat it.
你说什么
Pardon me?
我们不知道悲哀谷有没有食物
We don't know if there's food waiting at the hollow.
甚至不知道这是什么地方
We don't even know where we are.
他们不会让我们遇到危险的
They can't let anything happen to us.
这是户外团建
It's an ORTBO.
户外团建活动 马克 对吗
Outdoor retreat team-building occurrence. Right, Mark?
我们不知道这到底是什么
We don't know what this is.
- 我们什么都不知道 - 欧文 冷静
- We don't know anything! - Irving, calm down.
我们都知道你上次去外面时 经历了不好的事
We all know you had a bad experience the last time you were outside--
谁说我经历了不好的事
Who said I had a bad experience?
天啊
Oh, my God.
白痴 你对他说了什么
What did you tell him, dumbass?
什么都没说 你怎么了
Nothing! What the fuck?
我们去悲哀谷吧
Let's just get to the hollow.
基尔的双胞胎兄弟总是陪伴着他
Kier's twin was always with him.
所以我们也为你们每个人都提供了一位
That's why we provided the very same for each of you.
去你们的 我说对了
Fuck you all. I was right.
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick.
这是地球上最高的瀑布
This is the tallest waterfall on the planet.
你们已跟着基尔和迪特的脚步 到达了悲哀谷
You have followed the path of Kier and Dieter, and reached Woe's Hollow.
你们站在神圣的土地上
You stand upon sacred earth.
我们要饿死了 米尔奇克先生
We're starving, Mr. Milchick.
是吗
Are you?
我以为瀑布的壮阔美景 已经能让你们感到充实了
I thought the waterfall's grandeur would satiate you.
当然 我是在开玩笑
I'm teasing, of course.
卢蒙永远都会为你们提供保护和物资
Lumon will always protect and provide.
请走这边
Right this way.
黄小姐已经在准备烧烤架 我们送来了丰富的高级肉类
Miss Huang has been readying the grill for which we brought in copious luxury meats.
篝火将用于稍后的烤棉花糖和诵诗会
The fire will be used for marshmallows and a recital later.
正如你们可见的 帐篷是宏观数据精检的蓝色
The tents, as you can see, are MDR blue
户外厕所里配有了四层卫生纸
and the outhouse is stocked with four-ply washroom tissue.
天啊
Wow.
的确值得惊叹 赫莉R
Wow, indeed, Helly R.
此外 为了你们的舒适和安全 我们也提供火炬
Also, for your comfort and safety, torches,
可作为保暖和照明两用
which can provide both a heat and a light source.
一石二鸟
Double duty.
真美
It's beautiful.
挺酷的 对吗
Pretty cool, right?
是的 很棒
Yes, lovely.
欧文
Irving?
进来
Enter.
我给你做了个雪海豹
Made you a snow seal.
你饿了的话可以吃
In case you were hungry.
是
Yeah.
我之前提议吃那个动物 现在觉得好傻
I feel silly for suggesting we eat that animal.
感觉是在制造恐慌和被害妄想
I suppose it sounded alarmist and paranoid.
不理智
Irrational.
不 没事的 大家都有点...
No. It was fine. We were all a little...
对
Yeah.
你在紧急加班时真正看到了什么
What did you really see during the overtime contingency?
我已经告诉你了
I told you.
没事的
It's okay.
那不会改变什么的
It won't change anything.
欧文
Irving.
好吧
Okay.
“迪特没有清洗身体 躺在床铺上
"Dieter lay unwashed in his bedroll,
虽然悲哀谷的池子是理想的盥洗地点
though the hollow's pool was primed for bathing.
我们吃了之前捕猎到的野兔
We ate of the hare we'd caught
并说着押韵的玩笑话 直到喉咙沙哑
and told each other rhyming jokes till our gullets ached.
但最终我还是说出了一直在嘴边的话
But at last, the thought tickling my mouth emerged.
‘我们必须回到父亲身边’ 我说
'We must return to Father,' I said.
‘但我保证会在乙醚厂保护你’
'But I promise to look after you in the ether mill.'
他嘴里最后发出的声音是一声低低的哀嚎
When at last a sound came from him, it was a bewailing whimper.
我想 他以为我们会永远在野外流浪
He believed, I suppose, that we'd be woodland paupers forever.
我看着他 他的眼睛突了出来
I was looking at him when his eye came out.
眼球从眼窝里跳出来
It popped from the socket,
是被他头颅中突然涌出的脓水推出来的
driven by a sudden torrent of pus from his skull.
他抬手抓住自己的头发
And he reached up to grasp at his hair,
头发蓦然变成了青苔 轻易地从淌血的头皮上被扯下来”
which was suddenly moss that tore easily from his bleeding scalp."
我的娘啊
Good heavens.
“他眼窝中的脓水慢慢凝固
"And as the pus from his eye thickened into sap,
我离开喉咙中汩汩作响的兄弟 走向悲哀谷的池子
I turned from my gargling brother and walked to the pool of the hollow,
我知道瀑布的水声会掩盖我兄弟的哭嚎”
where I knew the waterfall would drown out my brother's cries."
这么做其实挺聪明
That's actually really smart.
“就在这里 我第一次遇到悲哀脾气
"And it was here that I first encountered the temper Woe,
她是一个憔悴的新娘 身高是普通女人的一半
a gaunt bride, half the height of a natural woman.
她用眼睛与我直接交谈 说道
She spoke to me directly from her eyes and said,
‘这是你的错
'This is your doing.
你纵容他的放荡任为
You suffered his wantonness.
现在他不是任何人的兄弟了
Now he's no one's brother.
他只是混乱身边的妓女’”
Only chaos's whore.'"
本章完
The end.
也许我们明早可以再读下一章...
Perhaps in the morning, we'll have time for the next chapter...
(第2章)
“基尔和偷盗的保姆”
"Kier and the Thieving Nanny."
好惊悚
Creepy.
米尔奇克先生 他兄弟真是这么死的吗
Did his brother really die that way, Mr. Milchick?
手册中加入了创始人生平的故事 以丰富我们的工作
The handbook enriches our work with tales of the founder's life.
每一个字都是真实的
Every word is truth.
抱歉 对不起
I'm sorry. Sorry.
赫莉
Helly.
什么
What?
- 赫莉R  - 你们...
- Helly R.? - You guys...
他融化了 对吗
He melted, right?
他变成了森林的一部分 就因为他手淫
He turned into the forest because he masturbated.
说真的 这是我听过最蠢的故事了
I mean, seriously, that's actually the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
对吧 他在自己兄弟面前打飞机...
Right? He jerked off in front of his brother...
然后为此被罚
and he got punished for it.
什...别这么说啊
Wha... You can't say that.
- 他刚说的 - 什... 的确
- He just said it. - Wha... He did.
我...这...
I... It's...
我们常常嘲笑自己不理解的事
You know, we often laugh at what we don't understand.
我以为我所了解的你们 会以更审慎的态度应对问题
The team I thought I knew would have processed more thoughtfully.
黄小姐
Miss Huang.
请把棉花糖拿来
The marshmallows, please.
扔到火里
Throw them in the fire.
米尔奇克先生 别这样嘛
Mr. Milchick, come on.
快扔吧 黄小姐
Now, Miss Huang.
- 天 - 为什么
- Oh, my... - Why?
棉花糖只提供给有团队精神的员工 迪伦
Marshmallows are for team players, Dylan.
不是随便就派发的
They don't just hand them out.
什么
What?
晚安
Good night.
天啊
Wow.
真开眼了
Oh, my God.
嘿 你们觉得他的老二变成了什么
Hey, what do you think his dick turned into?
不好笑
It isn't funny.
我不觉得 很好笑啊
I don't know. It's pretty funny.
- 并不好笑 - 好吧
- Well, it's not. - Okay.
而且别总是对她眉目传情
And stop making goo-goo eyes at her.
- 我没有 - 别这样
- I'm not. - Stop.
“眉目传情”
"Goo-goo eyes"?
赫莉 就告诉我们吧
Just tell us, Helly.
什么
What?
来 告诉我们
Come on. Tell us.
告诉我们什么
Tell us what?
把他的事告诉我们
Just tell us about him.
谁
Who?
夜班园丁
The night gardener.
欧文 拜托
Irv, come on.
他有电筒吗
Did he have a flashlight?
他穿着什么
What was he wearing?
哥们 你有什么毛病
What is your deal right now, dude?
他的上衣是什么颜色
What color was his shirt?
他穿了背心吗
Did he have on a vest?
- 夜光背心 告诉我们... - 好
- A luminescent vest? Tell us... - Okay.
- 他到底穿的什么... - 欧文 够了
- ...exactly what he was wear-- - Irving. That's enough.
- 够了  - 对
- Enough? - Yeah.
用你的瞳孔和她做爱
Using your pupils to make love to her
而你外面自己的老婆 此刻正在某个地方腐烂
while your outie's wife rots away somewhere.
嘿 闭嘴
Hey, shut up.
对 去你的 欧文
Yeah. Fuck you, Irv.
所以现在是三对一
So it's three against one now, huh?
没事
It's okay.
我们都知道欧文不开心 因为他再也见不到伯特了
We all know Irving's upset because he can't ever see Burt again.
他很孤单
And he's really lonely.
嘿 欧文
Hey, Irv.
你们都去死吧
Fuck you all.
可能是胡萝卜
Probably a carrot.
什么
What?
迪特的老二
Dieter's penis.
对 或其他根茎类植物
Yeah, or some other root vegetable.
我刚才那样很刻薄
That was mean of me...
对欧文说那种话
to say that to Irving.
他其实也是自找的
I mean, he kind of deserved it.
我想对谁眉目传情 他也管不着
And I can make goo-goo eyes at anyone I want.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
抱歉我分了你的心...
Sorry if I'm distracting you from...
分了什么心
From what?
你在找你的妻子
From looking for your wife.
嘿 没关系的
Hey, it's okay.
我知道我们会找到她 而且你已经帮了很多忙
I know we'll find her, and you've already helped so much.
有吗
I have?
有
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick!
黄小姐
Miss Huang!
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick!
黄小姐
Miss Huang!
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick!
我不喜欢外面的自己
I didn't like who I was on the outside.
我感到羞愧
I was ashamed.
你是谁
Who were you?
我不在乎你在外面是谁
I don't care who you are out there.
我只在乎我身边的你
I care who you are with me.
这就够了
That's all.
好吗
Okay?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
发生了什么
What happened?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
(蒙托克 完成进度:3% 卢蒙)
赫莉
Helly?
嘿 赫莉人呢
Hey, where's Helly?
我不知道 欧文昨晚没有回来 他也不在帐篷里
I don't know. Irv never came back last night, and he's not in his tent.
什么
What?
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick?
赫莉
Helly!
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick!
马克
Mark.
马克 迪伦 发生了什么
Mark. Dylan, what's happened?
赫莉和欧文不见了
Helly and Irv are missing.
到底发生了什么
What the fuck is going on?
嘿 孩子
Hey, kid.
欧文
Irving.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing down here?
我昨晚在外面过夜
I slept outside.
几乎冻死
I almost froze to death.
你昨晚对我说的话
What you said to me last night,
非常残忍
it was cruel.
过去的赫莉从不是残忍的人
Helly was never cruel.
我人就在这
I'm right here.
所以 如果你不是她
So if you're not her...
那你是谁
then who are you?
有谁拥有这么大的权力 能将外面的自己送到分离楼层
Who would have the power to send their outie to the severed floor?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
不 欧文
No! Irving!
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick!
- 不... - 跟我走
- No. No! - Come on.
- 欧文 停下 欧文 不 - 米尔奇克先生
- Irving. Stop. Irving, no. - Mr. Milchick!
请停下
Please, stop.
帮帮我
Help!
- 米尔奇克先生 - 不
- Mr. Milchick! - No!
欧文
Irving?
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick!
欧文
Irving!
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick!
- 过来 - 马克
- Come! - Mark!
米尔奇克先生
Mr. Milchick!
- 马克 - 赫莉
- Mark! - Helly!
- 把她变回来 米尔奇克先生 - 帮帮我
- Turn her back, Mr. Milchick! - Help!
哥们 你在做什么
What are you doing, man?
- 把她变回来 - 欧文 搞什么
- Turn her back! - Irv, what the fuck?
她是外面的自己
She's an outie!
- 嘿 欧文 停下 - 嘿 欧文 住手
- Hey! Irving, stop it! - Hey! Irv, cut it out!
- 停下 - 她一直都是外面的自己
- Stop! - She's been an outie the whole time,
打从回来起
ever since she came back!
- 欧文 立即停下 - 住手
- Irving, you stop now! - Stop it!
欧文 停下
Irving, stop this!
她是个间谍
She's a fucking mole!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
- 欧文 - 我要杀了她 米尔奇克先生
- Irving! - I'm gonna kill her, Mr. Milchick!
欧文...
Irving! Irving!
停下 住手
Stop! Stop this!
她不是赫莉
She's not Helly!
她是伊根家族的人
She's an Eagan!
把她变回来...米尔奇克先生
Turn her back, Mr. Milchick! Turn her back!
该死的 塞斯 动手吧
Goddamn it, Seth, do it!
对 动手吧 塞斯
Yes! Do it, Seth!
嘿
Hey!
我是米尔奇克 立即移除格拉斯哥屏障
It's Milchick. Remove the Glasgow block now.
马上
Now!
对不起
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉 赫莉
I'm so sorry, Helly.
发生了什么
What's happening?
赫莉
Helly!
对不起 赫莉
I'm sorry, Helly.
欧文B 起立
Irving B., stand.
你在悲哀谷的池子里威胁要杀害同事
You have threatened collegial murder in the pond of Woe's Hollow.
对此 唯一的惩罚是立即和永久罢免职位
For this, there can be no penalty but immediate and permanent dismissal.
将不会安排有餐饮或无餐饮的 正式离职送别会
There shall be no formal valediction, catered or otherwise.
你外面的自己将立即接获通知
Your outie will be notified forthwith.
欧文 对不起
Irv! I'm sorry!
我该听你的
I should have listened!
没事 没关系的
It's okay. It's all okay.
你们只要记得坚持下去
Just remember, hang in there.
请不要继续发表任何言论
Please refrain from any further speech,
因为你已失去与任何分离层员工 交流的权限
as you are no longer authorized to consort with any severed employee,
他们也不得与你交流
nor they with you.
不许命令他
Leave him alone!
转身
Turn around!
不许你命令他
Leave him alone!
走进森林
Walk into the forest.
你的工位将被清理
Your workspace will be cleared
任何私人物品将弃置
and any personal items discarded.
你的文件 包括任何及全部职业互动
Your file, including any and all professional interactions
和个人关系
and personal relations,
将被抹去和销毁
will be purged and destroyed.
你 欧文B
It will be as if you, Irving B.,
将仿佛从未存在过
never even existed
也从未在这个世界上呼吸过
nor drew a single breath upon this Earth.
愿基尔仁慈保佑你进入永恒黑暗
May Kier's mercy follow you into the eternal dark.
现在
Now.